# PAVANI PRUDHVI

Technical Product Owner | MVP | G2M | Product Roadmap | Data | B2B | B2C | Certified SAFe Agile
POPM | Azure Cloud platform | KPI

### CONTACT

### **PROFILE**

+1 862-405-0200

Pavaniprudhvi01@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/pavaniprudhvi/ Iselin. N.J Results-oriented Technical Product Owner with 9+ years of experience in B2C & B2B Product Management and strong skills in Designing Digital Product Strategies, Building Roadmaps, and Creating MVPs & Features.

Managed 6+ B2C and B2B Products across Edtech and Fintech throughout career, including a cloud Fintech Product that modernizes the data management process, and a data analytics product that delivers customized data solutions for 2 enterprise clients

### <u>SKILL</u>S

EXPERIENCE
-Data Product Owner, TD Bank

that impacts 60K+ end users.

Product Management Skills

User Research

Market Research

Competitor Analysis

Product Roadmap

MVP

Feature Design

Product Performance Metrics

Stakeholder Management

Requirement Elicitation

Sprint Planning & Estimation

Product Development Lifecycle

Leadership

Agile Methodologies

### **Technology and Tools**

SQL Server Management Studio

MS VISIO

Figma Prototyping

... 5 ...

Alteryx Desktop

Tableau Desktop

Azure Databricks

POSTMAN API Technology

ISON

Enterprise Data Catalogue (EDC)

Confluence

Google Analytics

UI/UX Reviews

MS Suite (Excel, Word, PPT)

## Achievement:

- Led the seamless, and secure data migration process from on-prem to Azure cloud, resulting in a 15% reduction in migration timelines & 25% increase in data accuracy
- Re-designed DaaS Data Intake processes and reduced the project delays by 20% and enhanced the accuracy of Adhoc project handoffs by 30%

## Responsibilities: 5-7 responsibilities

- Managing a cloud migration Product that modernizes the data management process at TD
- Set the Product Vision and developed 6+ MVPs for the cloud Fintech Product
  by leading a cross functional team of 10 Data Engineers, Business Information
  Analysts, Off-shore Testing team and Business Systems Analyst to strategize the
  cloud migration for loan collections and database.
- Contributed to **Product Roadmap** alongside Product Managers, Product Group Owners and fellow PO's
- Identified Data Use Cases adhering the Product Group's Azure Cloud Migration Product Strategies, and planned relevant training sessions and AD groups for access needs for all the POD members
- Designed & Presented 20 + Epics and corresponding User Stories during Pre-Pl and PI planning session
- Achieved 80% of the targeted KPIs throughout all the phases of the cloud migration process
- Responsible for hosting daily standups, monthly retrospectives, and Bi-weekly Backlog grooming sessions
- Gather and analyze Data & Reporting requirements from Internal Stakeholders and translate those into Technical requirements in BRDs, and Communicate those requirements to Kanban Teams
- Designed Market share Reports for Loan collection Line of Business, leveraging the data & Insights to enhance the Business Operations
- Present the User stories in Pipeline, Dependency Matrix, Impact Analysis, Impediments and Risk & Limitations to senior leaders and Product Group Owners on weekly basis

# Product Owner, Mercer Financial Services Achievement:

Jun 2021 - Dec 2022

April 2023 - Present

Led the development and deployment of customized data solutions, driving a 30% improvement in client decision-making accuracy, resulting in a revenue increase of \$2 million

A 4	

### Responsibilities:

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams for Master Data Management (MDM)
   Implementation for financial Data via EDC
- Led Agile Ceremonies for DnA Scrum Team of 7 and hosted daily stand-ups,
   Sprint Planning, Retrospectives, and Backlog Refinement sessions
- Maintained product backlogs in JIRA and tracked Team Velocity on sprint basis to improve the team's efficiency
- Overseen Data Validation Testing, including reconciliation of Data Types, character lengths, and business transformation logic on all data conversion attributes to ensure proper ETL Handling
- Owned and investigated data defects and their respective root cause analysis, partnering with Analytics 360 teams to complete all required documentation for resolution
- Handled End-End product Delivery from Data Requirement Gathering till Post-Production Testing and support

#### **EDUCATION**

**RGUKT-APIIIT, India**Bachelor of Technology

Sydney Business School, Australia

MBA Analytics

# Product Owner, University of Wollongong, Australia Feb 2019 – May 2021 Achievements:

- Directed UX/UI enhancements tailored to student preferences through A/B
   Testing, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement
- Facilitated personalized content delivery to enhance student/staff experience, resulting in a 15% improvement in student conversion rates

### Responsibilities:

- Conducted workshops and market research targeting Indian student market, ensuring alignment with cultural nuances and driving a 10% increase in student acquisition from India
- Overseen implementation of Moodle LMS, and other University Student Apps optimizing conversion rates and reducing onboarding time by 30% for Indian students
- Selected student segment to participate in UAT Testing and overseen the Testing processes
- Effectively handled REST APIs and API gateway integrating to third party products and conducted API testing through POSTMAP

## QA&E/BA, Cognizant Technology Solutions

Jan 2015 – Dec 2018

Client: Chubb insurance

- Led an ad-hoc project to design and deliver a Solution Quality Assurance application, resulting in a 25% reduction in project processing time and increasing employee participation by 30%
- Gather the functional requirements and Translate the Orchestrated User
   Acceptance Testing (UAT) on new feature releases, leading to a 20% decrease
   in post-launch production issues
- Mentored 3 trainees in Software Testing activities, resulting in a 20% improvement in test schedules adherence and application functionalities
- Supervised and led all aspects of STLC for multiple projects, ensuring successful completion and client satisfaction
- Analyze JSON file and perform API Testing in POSTMAP